<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Informational Whale App</string>
    <string name="baleen_whales">Baleen Whales</string>
    <string name="toothed_whales">Toothed Whales</string>
    <string name="whaleappsplashscreen">WhaleAppSplashScreen</string>
    <string name="BowheadWhale">bowhead</string>
    <string name="bowhead">Bowhead</string>
    <string name="OrcaWhale">orca</string>
    <string name="spermwhale">spermwhale</string>
    <string name="sperm_whale">Sperm Whale</string>
    <string name="orca">Orca</string>
    <string name="BeakedWhale">beakedwhale</string>
    <string name="GrayWhale">graywhale</string>
    <string name="Humpbackwhale">humpbackwhale</string>
    <string name="beaked">Beaked</string>
    <string name="gray">Gray</string>
    <string name="humpback">Humpback</string>
    <string name="baleenwhales">baleenwhales</string>
    <string name="toothedwhale">toothedwhale</string>
    <string name="select_a_whale_type_or_use_the_search_bar">Select a whale type or use the search bar</string>
    <string name="whaleapp">WhaleApp</string>
    <string name="daily_whale_fact">Daily Whale Fact</string>
    <string name="gray_whales_make_the_longest_annual_migration_of_any_mammal_and_travel_an_average_of_16000km">Gray Whales make the longest annual migration of any mammal and travel an average of 16000km!</string>
    <string name="summary">Summary:</string>
    <string name="beaked_whales_are_a_group_of_cetaceans_noted_as_being_one_of_the_least_known_groups_of_mammals_because_of_their_deep_sea_habitat_and_apparent_low_abundance_only_three_or_four_of_the_22_species_are_reasonably_well_known_baird_s_beaked_whales_and_cuvier_s_beaked_whales_were_subject_to_commercial_exploitation_off_the_coast_of_japan_while_the_northern_bottlenose_whale_was_extensively_hunted_in_the_northern_part_of_the_north_atlantic_late_in_the_19th_and_early_20th_centuries">Beaked whales are a group of cetaceans noted as being one of the least known groups of mammals because of their deep-sea habitat and apparent low abundance. Only three or four of the 22 species are reasonably well-known. Baird\'s beaked whales and Cuvier\'s beaked whales were subject to commercial exploitation, off the coast of Japan, while the northern bottlenose whale was extensively hunted in the northern part of the North Atlantic late in the 19th and early 20th centuries.</string>
    <string name="diet">Diet:</string>
    <string name="their_preferred_diet_is_primarily_deep_water_squid_but_also_benthic_and_benthopelagic_fish_and_some_crustaceans_mostly_taken_near_the_sea_floor_in_a_recent_study_gouge_marks_in_the_sea_floor_were_interpreted_to_be_a_result_of_feeding_activities_by_beaked_whales">Their preferred diet is primarily deep-water squid, but also benthic and benthopelagic fish and some crustaceans, mostly taken near the sea floor. In a recent study, gouge marks in the sea floor were interpreted to be a result of feeding activities by beaked whales.</string>
    <string name="habitat">Habitat:</string>
    <string name="beaked_whales_are_known_to_congregate_in_deep_waters_off_the_edge_of_continental_shelves_and_bottom_features_such_as_seamounts_canyons_escarpments_and_oceanic_islands_including_the_azores_and_the_canary_islands_and_even_off_the_coasts_of_hawaii">Beaked whales are known to congregate in deep waters off the edge of continental shelves, and bottom features, such as seamounts, canyons, escarpments, and oceanic islands, including the Azores and the Canary Islands, and even off the coasts of Hawaii.</string>
    <string name="behavior">Behavior:</string>
    <string name="a_new_study_suggests_that_beaked_whales_have_evolved_stealthy_and_synchronized_behavior_to_evade_predators_such_as_killer_whales_they_dive_in_synch_to_maximize_their_foraging_time_together_and_minimize_their_time_at_the_surface_where_killer_whales_can_more_easily_target_them">A new study suggests that beaked whales have evolved stealthy and synchronized behavior to evade predators such as killer whales. They dive in synch to maximize their foraging time together and minimize their time at the surface, where killer whales can more easily target them.</string>
    <string name="fun_fact">Fun Fact:</string>
    <string name="beaked_whales_are_also_the_deepest_diving_mammal_in_the_world_able_to_dive_at_a_depth_of_approximately_10_000_feet_3_048_meters_moreover_a_study_conducted_in_2014_has_shown_that_this_animal_is_the_longest_known_mammal_to_hold_its_breath_under_water">beaked whales are also the deepest diving mammal in the world, able to dive at a depth of approximately 10,000 feet (3, 048 meters). Moreover, a study, conducted in 2014, has shown that this animal is the longest known mammal to hold its breath under water.</string>
    <string name="the_bowhead_whale_balaena_mysticetus_is_a_species_of_baleen_whale_belonging_to_the_family_balaenidae_and_the_only_living_representative_of_the_genus_balaena_it_is_the_only_baleen_whale_endemic_to_the_arctic_and_subarctic_waters_bowheads_are_named_after_their_characteristic_massive_triangular_skull_which_is_used_to_break_through_arctic_ice_other_common_names_of_the_species_are_the_greenland_right_whale_or_arctic_whale_american_whalemen_called_them_the_steeple_top_polar_whale_or_russia_or_russian_whale">The bowhead whale (Balaena mysticetus) is a species of baleen whale belonging to the family Balaenidae and the only living representative of the genus Balaena. It is the only baleen whale endemic to the Arctic and subarctic waters. Bowheads are named after their characteristic massive triangular skull, which is used to break through Arctic ice. Other common names of the species are the Greenland right whale or Arctic whale. American whalemen called them the steeple-top, polar whale, or Russia or Russian whale.</string>
    <string name="the_diet_consists_of_mostly_zooplankton_which_includes_copepods_amphipods_and_many_other_crustaceans_about_2_short_tons_1_8_long_tons_1_8_t_of_food_are_consumed_each_day">The diet consists of mostly zooplankton, which includes copepods, amphipods, and many other crustaceans. About 2 short tons (1.8 long tons; 1.8 t) of food are consumed each day.</string>
    <string name="the_bowhead_whale_is_the_only_baleen_whale_to_spend_its_entire_life_in_the_arctic_and_subarctic_waters_the_alaskan_population_spends_the_winter_months_in_the_southwestern_bering_sea_the_group_migrates_northward_in_the_spring_following_openings_in_the_ice_into_the_chukchi_and_beaufort_seas_the_whale_s_range_varies_depending_on_climate_changes_and_on_the_forming_melting_of_ice">The bowhead whale is the only baleen whale to spend its entire life in the Arctic and subarctic waters. The Alaskan population spends the winter months in the southwestern Bering Sea. The group migrates northward in the spring, following openings in the ice, into the Chukchi and Beaufort seas. The whale\'s range varies depending on climate changes and on the forming/melting of ice.</string>
    <string name="bowhead_whales_are_not_social_animals_typically_travelling_alone_or_in_small_pods_of_up_to_six_they_are_able_to_dive_and_remain_submerged_under_water_for_up_to_an_hour_the_time_spent_under_water_in_a_single_dive_is_usually_limited_to_9_18_minutes">Bowhead whales are not social animals, typically travelling alone or in small pods of up to six. They are able to dive and remain submerged under water for up to an hour. The time spent under water in a single dive is usually limited to 9–18 minutes.</string>
    <string name="bowheads_have_the_largest_mouth_of_any_animal_representing_almost_one_third_of_the_length_of_the_body_the_longest_baleen_plates_with_a_maximum_length_of_4_m_13_1_ft_and_may_be_the_longest_lived_mammals_with_the_ability_to_reach_an_age_of_more_than_200_years">Bowheads have the largest mouth of any animal representing almost one-third of the length of the body, the longest baleen plates with a maximum length of 4 m (13.1 ft) and may be the longest-lived mammals, with the ability to reach an age of more than 200 years.</string>
    <string name="gray_whales_have_no_dorsal_back_fins_instead_they_have_a_low_hump_and_a_series_of_six_to_twelve_knuckles_or_bumps_gray_whales_are_baleen_whales_and_each_has_approximately_300_plates_of_cream_colored_baleen_hanging_from_its_upper_jaw_two_to_five_throat_creases_allow_their_throats_to_expand_during_feeding">Gray whales have no dorsal (back) fins. Instead, they have a low hump and a series of six to twelve knuckles or bumps. Gray whales are baleen whales, and each has approximately 300 plates of cream-colored baleen hanging from its upper jaw. Two to five throat creases allow their throats to expand during feeding.</string>
    <string name="amphipods_which_are_very_small_crustaceans_resembling_shrimp_make_up_90_of_their_diet_they_find_these_amphipods_in_the_mud_at_depths_of_about_200_feet_in_arctic_waters_especially_in_the_bering_sea_and_the_chukchi_sea">Amphipods, which are very small crustaceans resembling shrimp, make up 90% of their diet. They find these amphipods in the mud at depths of about 200 feet in arctic waters, especially in the Bering Sea and the Chukchi Sea.</string>
    <string name="gray_whales_are_found_mainly_in_shallow_coastal_waters_in_the_north_pacific_ocean_there_are_two_geographic_distributions_of_gray_whales_in_the_north_pacific_the_eastern_north_pacific_stock_found_along_the_west_coast_of_north_america_and_the_western_north_pacific_stock_found_along_the_coast_of_eastern_asia">Gray whales are found mainly in shallow coastal waters in the North Pacific Ocean. There are two geographic distributions of gray whales in the North Pacific: the eastern North Pacific stock, found along the west coast of North America, and the western North Pacific stock, found along the coast of eastern Asia.</string>
    <string name="gray_whales_are_frequently_observed_traveling_alone_or_in_small_unstable_groups_although_large_aggregations_may_be_seen_in_feeding_and_breeding_grounds_like_other_baleen_whales_long_term_bonds_between_individuals_are_thought_to_be_rare">Gray whales are frequently observed traveling alone or in small, unstable groups, although large aggregations may be seen in feeding and breeding grounds. Like other baleen whales, long-term bonds between individuals are thought to be rare.</string>
    <string name="adult_grey_whales_can_be_as_long_as_15_meters_and_weigh_up_to_35_tones_stack_five_male_african_elephants_onto_a_scale_and_you_get_the_picture_female_grey_whales_are_slightly_bigger_than_males">Adult grey whales can be as long as 15 meters and weigh up to 35 tones. Stack five male African elephants onto a scale and you get the picture. Female grey whales are slightly bigger than males.</string>
    <string name="humpbacks_are_mainly_black_or_grey_with_white_undersides_to_their_flukes_flippers_and_bellies_they_are_15m_long_humpback_whales_are_extremely_active_often_slapping_their_flippers_and_flukes_on_the_surface_of_the_sea_they_also_breach_more_than_any_other_baleen_whales">Humpbacks are mainly black or grey with white undersides to their flukes, flippers and bellies. They are 15m long. ... Humpback whales are extremely active, often slapping their flippers and flukes on the surface of the sea. They also breach more than any other baleen whales.</string>
    <string name="humpback_whales_filter_feed_on_small_crustaceans_mostly_krill_and_small_fish_consuming_up_to_3_000_pounds_of_food_per_day_humpback_whales_use_various_techniques_to_help_them_herd_corral_and_disorient_their_prey_which_can_involve_the_use_of_bubbles_sounds_and_even_their_pectoral_fins">Humpback whales filter-feed on small crustaceans (mostly krill) and small fish, consuming up to 3,000 pounds of food per day. Humpback whales use various techniques to help them herd, corral, and disorient their prey, which can involve the use of bubbles, sounds, and even their pectoral fins.</string>
    <string name="humpback_whales_live_along_the_coasts_of_all_oceans_occasionally_swimming_close_to_shore_even_into_harbors_and_rivers_they_undertake_long_migrations_between_polar_feeding_grounds_in_summer_and_tropical_or_subtropical_breeding_grounds_in_winter">Humpback whales live along the coasts of all oceans, occasionally swimming close to shore, even into harbors and rivers. They undertake long migrations between polar feeding grounds in summer and tropical or subtropical breeding grounds in winter.</string>
    <string name="humpback_whales_usually_feed_beneath_the_surface_of_the_water_finding_groups_of_prey_and_gulping_them_down_however_some_dynamic_feeding_behaviors_may_be_observed_at_the_surface_when_lunge_feeding_a_humpback_propels_itself_rapidly_through_a_concentrated_ball_or_group_of_fish_or_krill_with_its_mouth_wide_open">Humpback whales usually feed beneath the surface of the water, finding groups of prey and gulping them down. However, some dynamic feeding behaviors may be observed at the surface. When lunge feeding, a humpback propels itself rapidly through a concentrated ball or group of fish or krill with its mouth wide open.</string>
    <string name="humpback_whales_are_not_the_biggest_whales_that_s_the_blue_whale_humpbacks_can_grow_to_60_feet_18_meters_long_and_they_can_weigh_a_whopping_40_tons_about_half_the_size_of_a_blue_whale_according_to_the_noaa_their_flippers_can_grow_up_to_16_feet_5_m_long_which_is_the_largest_appendage_in_the_world">Humpback whales are not the biggest whales — that\'s the blue whale. Humpbacks can grow to 60 feet (18 meters) long, and they can weigh a whopping 40 tons (about half the size of a blue whale), according to the NOAA. Their flippers can grow up to 16 feet (5 m) long, which is the largest appendage in the world.</string>
    <string name="the_killer_whale_or_orca_orcinus_orca_is_a_toothed_whale_belonging_to_the_oceanic_dolphin_family_of_which_it_is_the_largest_member_killer_whales_have_a_diverse_diet_although_individual_populations_often_specialize_in_particular_types_of_prey_some_feed_exclusively_on_fish_while_others_hunt_marine_mammals_such_as_seals_and_other_species_of_dolphin_they_have_been_known_to_attack_baleen_whale_calves_and_even_adult_whales">The killer whale or orca (Orcinus orca) is a toothed whale belonging to the oceanic dolphin family, of which it is the largest member. Killer whales have a diverse diet, although individual populations often specialize in particular types of prey. Some feed exclusively on fish, while others hunt marine mammals such as seals and other species of dolphin. They have been known to attack baleen whale calves, and even adult whales.</string>
    <string name="on_average_a_killer_whale_eats_227_kilograms_500_lb_each_day_killer_whales_prey_on_around_30_species_of_fish_salmon_account_for_96_of_northeast_pacific_residents_diet_including_65_of_large_fatty_chinook_chum_salmon_are_also_eaten_but_smaller_sockeye_and_pink_salmon_are_not_a_significant_food_item">On average, a killer whale eats 227 kilograms (500 lb) each day. killer whales prey on around 30 species of fish. Salmon account for 96% of northeast Pacific residents\' diet, including 65% of large, fatty Chinook. Chum salmon are also eaten, but smaller sockeye and pink salmon are not a significant food item.</string>
    <string name="killer_whales_are_found_in_all_oceans_and_most_seas_due_to_their_enormous_range_numbers_and_density_relative_distribution_is_difficult_to_estimate_but_they_clearly_prefer_higher_latitudes_and_coastal_areas_over_pelagic_environments_areas_which_serve_as_major_study_sites_for_the_species_include_the_coasts_of_iceland_norway_the_valdes_peninsula_of_argentina_the_crozet_islands_new_zealand_and_parts_of_the_west_coast_of_north_america_from_california_to_alaska">Killer whales are found in all oceans and most seas. Due to their enormous range, numbers, and density, relative distribution is difficult to estimate but they clearly prefer higher latitudes and coastal areas over pelagic environments. Areas which serve as major study sites for the species include the coasts of Iceland, Norway, the Valdes Peninsula of Argentina, the Crozet Islands, New Zealand and parts of the west coast of North America, from California to Alaska.</string>
    <string name="day_to_day_killer_whale_behavior_generally_consists_of_foraging_travelling_resting_and_socializing_killer_whales_frequently_engage_in_surface_behavior_such_as_breaching_jumping_completely_out_of_the_water_and_tail_slapping_these_activities_may_have_a_variety_of_purposes_such_as_courtship_communication_dislodging_parasites_or_play_spy_hopping_is_a_behavior_in_which_a_whale_holds_its_head_above_water_to_view_its_surroundings_resident_killer_whales_swim_alongside_porpoises_and_other_dolphins">Day-to-day killer whale behavior generally consists of foraging, travelling, resting and socializing. Killer whales frequently engage in surface behavior such as breaching (jumping completely out of the water) and tail-slapping. These activities may have a variety of purposes, such as courtship, communication, dislodging parasites, or play. Spy hopping is a behavior in which a whale holds its head above water to view its surroundings. Resident killer whales swim alongside porpoises and other dolphins.</string>
    <string name="orca_s_aren_t_really_whales_they_also_cannot_smell_but_they_do_have_big_brains">Orca’s aren’t really whales. They also cannot smell, but they do have big brains.</string>
    <string name="the_sperm_whale_or_cachalot_physeter_macrocephalus_is_the_largest_of_the_toothed_whales_and_the_largest_toothed_predator_it_is_the_only_living_member_of_the_genus_physeter_and_one_of_three_extant_species_in_the_sperm_whale_family">The sperm whale or cachalot (Physeter macrocephalus) is the largest of the toothed whales and the largest toothed predator. It is the only living member of the genus Physeter and one of three extant species in the sperm whale family</string>
    <string name="sperm_whales_usually_dive_between_300_to_800_meters_980_to_2_620_ft_and_sometimes_1_to_2_kilometers_3_300_to_6_600_ft_in_search_of_food_such_dives_can_last_more_than_an_hour_they_feed_on_several_species_notably_the_giant_squid_but_also_the_colossal_squid_octopuses_and_fish_such_as_demersal_rays_but_their_diet_is_mainly_medium_sized_squid">Sperm whales usually dive between 300 to 800 meters (980 to 2,620 ft), and sometimes 1 to 2 kilometers (3,300 to 6,600 ft), in search of food. Such dives can last more than an hour. They feed on several species, notably the giant squid, but also the colossal squid, octopuses, and fish such as demersal rays, but their diet is mainly medium-sized squid</string>
    <string name="sperm_whales_have_one_of_the_widest_global_distributions_of_any_marine_mammal_species_they_are_found_in_all_deep_oceans_from_the_equator_to_the_edge_of_the_pack_ice_in_the_arctic_and_antarctic">sperm whales have one of the widest global distributions of any marine mammal species. They are found in all deep oceans, from the equator to the edge of the pack ice in the Arctic and Antarctic.</string>
    <string name="like_elephants_females_and_their_young_live_in_matriarchal_groups_called_pods_while_bulls_live_apart_bulls_sometimes_form_loose_bachelor_groups_with_other_males_of_similar_age_and_size_as_they_grow_older_they_typically_live_solitary_lives_only_returning_to_the_pod_to_socialize_or_to_breed_bulls_have_beached_themselves_together_suggesting_a_degree_of_cooperation_which_is_not_yet_fully_understood_the_whales_rarely_if_ever_leave_their_group">Like elephants, females and their young live in matriarchal groups called pods, while bulls live apart. Bulls sometimes form loose bachelor groups with other males of similar age and size. As they grow older, they typically live solitary lives, only returning to the pod to socialize or to breed . Bulls have beached themselves together, suggesting a degree of cooperation which is not yet fully understood. The whales rarely, if ever, leave their group.</string>
    <string name="sperm_whales_are_the_largest_of_the_toothed_whales_males_can_weigh_up_to_50_tons_which_is_more_than_700_people_combined_their_head_is_about_one_third_of_their_body_length_and_they_have_the_largest_brain_of_any_animal_on_earth">Sperm whales are the largest of the toothed whales. Males can weigh up to 50 tons, which is more than 700 people combined. Their head is about one-third of their body length, and they have the largest brain of any animal on Earth.</string>
    <string name="my_whale_log">My Whale Log</string>
    <string name="sperm_whale_">Sperm Whale</string>
    <string name="beaked_">Beaked</string>
    <string name="bowhead_">Bowhead</string>
    <string name="grey_whale_">Grey Whale</string>
    <string name="humpback_">Humpback</string>
    <string name="orca_">Orca</string>
    <string name="my_whale_log_">My Whale Log</string>
</resources>